（A24影业）
（探戈娱乐）
（高频娱乐）
（大海滩公司）
（帕斯特尔公司）
出品公司
A24影业
探戈娱乐 高频娱乐 大海滩公司
制作公司
帕斯特尔公司
字幕译制
蒙太奇字幕组
用 爱 发 电 ♥ Powered by love
Oh, my God! Hi!
天呐 你终于到了
Fuck, it's fucking cold!
我去 冷死我了
Ahhh!
啊 啊 啊
- You made it! - I made it!
- 终于来了 - 终于来了
I missed you!
我想死你了
- Oh, my God, I missed you, I missed you! - Yay!
- 天呐 我也想你 超想你 - 耶
Help me, it's fucking cold!
搭把手 冷死我了
I cannot believe you still live here.
你竟然还住在这儿
Yeah, well, you say that every time.
嗯 你每次都这么说
I can't feel my fucking hands, ah! shit me.
手都冻麻了 啊 该死的
Let me take that. Let me take that.
我来拿吧 让我来拿
It's really heavy.
可重了
Yeah, fuck, it is heavy.
是啊 重的要命
Did you bring me presents?
里面是给我带的礼物吗？
Oh, no, just like eighteen pairs of socks.
哦 不是 就一大堆袜子
I have socks.
这儿有的是袜子
Yeah, but your feet are huge, babe.
是 但宝贝你的尺码太大了
“宝贝”相伴的时光
It's really heavy.
可真重呀
Oh, my God.
天呐
- This is what I think. - Yeah.
- 我是这么想的 - 嗯
When you are having sex with a guy...
跟男人做爱的时候...
Yeah.
嗯
- Sometimes... - Mhmm.
- 有时... - 嗯哼
They are saying stuff like,
他们会突然冒出句...
"You like that."
“喜欢吧”
Mhmm.
嗯？
You like that.
就知道你喜欢
Mhmm. What is that, even?
嗯 到底啥意思
Right.
对
Oh, that's deep.
哦 懂了 太爹味了
I think... I think they mean
我觉得 他们是说...
you like...
说我喜欢...
- That. - That.
- 那玩意儿 - 那玩意儿
- Yeah. "You like my dick." - Or that.
- 对 说你喜欢他的鸡鸡 - 那东西
But it's like, they like, it's like, also their dick is their whole self.
就好像 他们把那玩意儿当成是自己的一切
So they're like, "Do you like the dick? Do you like me?"
“喜欢我的鸡鸡吧”等同于“喜欢我吧”
- "Do you love me?" - "Do you love me!"
- “爱我吧” - 得了吧
"And I am fucking you with my dick."
那意思是“用我的鸡鸡爱你”
Right.
对
And sometimes it's like...
那爱就像...
Don't.
别
No, sometimes it's like...
或者像...
Oh, God.
天呐
Sometimes it's like...
有时像...
Kinda.
像吧
- No. It is. - It's like...
- 可不是嘛 - 像这...
Sometimes it's like you leave your mind and you're like, seeing it from, like,
有时感觉自己灵魂出窍 从他眼里...
- perspective behind. - Inside their brain.
- 他的视角 - ...看自己
Your butt looks weird.
看自己屁股可怪了
Sometimes it's like... right!
有时还...对 哈哈
So, are you gonna let me read it?
那我什么时候能看？
Yeah. But it's not done.
别急 还没好呢
It's not even a proper draft.
连正式稿都算不上
But it's a draft.
但总归是个稿子
It's definitely a draft.
可不是嘛
Is it still about gay New York stuff?
还是那种纽约同性恋题材吗？
Yeah, but now it's, like, dark and like psychological, but also funny.
对 不过这次更黑暗 偏心理化 也很幽默
I will need to read that.
我绝对要看
Ahoy!
船来了！
【译注 Ahoy源自17世纪海员打招呼】
Is that guy talking to us?
他在跟我们说话吗？
Ugh, I think he just said, "Ahoy."
呃 他好像喊了句船来了
Ahoy there, neighbor!
嘿 邻居 船来了
Ahoy!
船来了
Ugh, he's in our spot.
唉 他占了我们的树
Fuckin' hell.
天杀的
I wish you still lived here.
真想你还住在这儿
Yeah.
嗯
Or closer, at least.
哪怕住近点
Yeah, I wish you lived closer to me too.
嗯 我也想你搬去我那
I like it here, though.
不过我还是喜欢这儿
Are you sure?
你确定？
Why?
怎么了？
It's a lot, right?
压力很大 对吧？
Still being here.
待在这里的话
Well, it's a lot to be wherever.
在哪儿都不轻松
Yeah. That's true.
嗯 的确
School was like...
研究生院真让人
- Ugh, Grad school was... - Ugh.
- 呃 让人作呕 - 呃
Exactly.
没错
Do you miss me even though you're married?
你结完婚还会想我吗？
Yes, I miss you even though I'm married.
会呀 即便结了婚 还是会想你啊
Married.
都结婚了
- Ugh. - So grown up.
- 哎 - 都变成大人了
It's so grown up.
真变成大人了
Hey! Hey, you over there!
嘿 嘿 那边的
I'm married!
我结婚了
I'm in a union that the state knows about!
刚领过证了
My dad is divorced.
我爸离婚了
Oh, that's sad.
哦 真惨
That's okay.
没关系的
Well, what do we do now?
那么 我们现在怎么办？
【译注 电影《十二怒汉》（1957）陪审员辩证真相与偏见】
You're alone.
就你一人了
I don't care whether I'm alone or not.
我不管
It's my right.
这是我的权利
It's your right.
对 是你的权利
What do you want? I say he's guilty.
你们想咋样 我就认定他有罪
I wanna hear your arguments.
讲讲你的理由
I gave you my...
我说过我...
（《洛丽塔》）
【译注 《洛丽塔》：纳博科夫（美籍俄裔）描绘未成年人性剥削的争议之作】
Ew.
真恶心
（《洛丽塔》）
Yes...
来了
Oh.
咦
- Hi. - Hi.
- 你好 - 你好
- Can I help you? - Uh, no. I'm sorry.
- 有事吗？ - 呃 没 抱歉
Do I have the wrong house?
我敲错门了吗？
No. This is the right house.
是这户没错啊
- Are you... - Wait.
- 你是... - 等下
No. No.
完了 完了
Oh, no. no, no, no, no.
哦 别 别 别
This is the house, yeah.
就是这门啊
- Are you looking for Agnes? - Yes, yeah.
- 你找安尼丝吗？ - 对 是
Gavin!
盖文
- Agnes. - Lydie.
- 你好呀 安尼丝 - 我是利迪
Oh, you're Lydie. Oh, my God!
哦 你就是利迪 真尴尬
Okay, I am so sorry, this is the weekend.
抱歉 因为周末又到了
Yeah.
是啊
My mistake.
看来我错了
No problem. Gavin is my neighbor.
没事 盖文是我邻居
Gavin, you actually live over there.
盖文 别忘了你住那边
Oh, yes. I live there.
哦 对 我住那边
- Oops. - That's okay.
- 敲错了 - 没关系
Sweet dreams, Gavin.
做个好梦吧 盖文
God bless your lost soul, and have a good night.
愿上帝管管你这可怜的灵魂 拜拜
- It's nice to meet you, Lydie. - You too.
- 很高兴见到你 利迪 - 我也是
He's cute.
他真可爱
- Who? - You're fucking him.
- 他？- 你找他来上床的
No, I'm not.
不 才没有
- You're fucking your neighbor. - No, I'm not.
- 把邻居找来上床的 - 不 没这事儿
You're fucking your neighbor named Gavin.
你想和邻居盖文上床
You are.
是你想吧
I'm not. I'm not.
才不是 才不是
- No. I'm not. - You are fucking him.
- 那我也没 - 你就是想
- I'm not. - You're fucking Gavin!
- 才不想 - 你就是想和他上床
- Agnes. - Mhmm.
- 安尼丝 - 嗯
I need to talk to you about something.
我得跟你说件事
Okay.
好
Okay. So it's about my body.
嗯 是关于我身体的事
Oh, your body is perfect.
哦 你身材很棒
Oh, thank you.
哦 谢谢
But, um, I didn't mean it like that.
但 呃 我不是那个意思
Okay...
好
So I have a baby in me.
我肚子里有个宝宝
- You do? - Yeah.
- 怀了？ - 是啊
What? Right now?
什么？现在就怀了吗？
Right now.
现在
- Yeah. - What?!
- 嗯 - 真假的
Oh, my God.
天呐
Oh, my God. Your body is a miracle.
天呐 你的身体真是个奇迹
Oh, my God.
天呐
Are you scared?
你紧张吗？
Yeah, yeah.
嗯 有点
Oh, but are you glad?
但也很开心吧？
Yeah, yes. It's good.
嗯 是呀 挺好的
Like, I wanted it, obviously.
显然这是我想要的
Like, we tried a million times.
费了好大劲
Yeah. You did want it.
对 你确实想要
- Yeah. - Lydie...
- 对 - 利迪
Are you gonna name it Agnes?
打算用我的名字吗？
Oh.
哦
Yeah. I don't know. I don't know.
嗯 我不知道 我不确定
Try and think about it.
别急着拒绝
So it must have been good sperm.
捐的精子质量肯定不错
Yeah. Thank God for that
对啊 幸好如此
random, tall white guy's good sperm.
某个高个儿白人的好精子
Maybe I should have his babies too
要不我也用他的生个孩子
and then they can be brothers.
正好当兄弟
Well, he's pretty hard to track down, so.
都是匿名的
Well, we have his picture, so we could look him up.
有照片嘛 能把他找出来
Can I touch it?
能摸摸吗？
Yeah.
好啊
I don't really feel anything.
我什么都感觉不到
That's because it's not like a baby yet.
因为还没长成个小宝宝
How old is it?
多大了？
Ten weeks?
有十周吧
So probably really small.
所以估计挺小的
Yeah.
对
What, like a mouse maybe?
像老鼠那么大？
How big is a mouse?
老鼠有多大来着？
Oh, it's smaller than that.
哦 比那还小
Wow, smaller than a mouse.
哇 竟然比老鼠小
Don't tell anyone tonight about...
今晚可别跟任何人提这个
Oh, don't worry.
放心吧
I never tell secrets
我从不乱说秘密
unless I feel it is a secret I really wanna tell.
除非我真想讲
That is not reassuring, babe.
这话听着一点也不让人放心 宝贝
I don't wanna go.
我真不想去
No!
不行
No, we have to. Natasha will kill me.
不行 得去 不然娜塔莎会把我宰了
I feel like... I feel like she's, like, rude,
我觉得 她给人感觉态度不好
like, tonally.
说话带刺
Oh, she definitely has a very rude tone.
可不是 她讲话可刺人了
Right?
对吧
She's got a really rude tone.
她说话语气真有问题
Are you afraid?
你怕吗？
Yeah.
有点
For the pain?
是怕疼吗？
Yeah.
是啊
But also because it's like, a person.
但这是个独立的人啊
I wanna make a really good person.
我想养出个好人
You're gonna make a good person.
你会把孩子带成好人的
It's gonna hurt so bad.
会疼得要命的
Oh, my God, it seems like it hurts so bad!
可不是 会疼死你的
No! Don't say that.
不 别这么说
I'm allowed to say that,
我能说
you're not allowed to say that.
不许你说
Blah, blah, blah. Doesn't matter.
废话不说
Short story is, we got the house,
简而言之 房子买到了
but we had to pay, like, significantly more than we wanted to.
但花的比我们预期多得多
Do you like this house? My house?
喜欢这房子吧？我家的！
I, I do. Yeah. Oh, my God.
嗯 挺喜欢的
The wood... it's gorgeous.
木头 好有质感
It's rich. Like dark.
高档的 很奢华
Yeah.
嗯
What are you gonna put in it?
准备搬哪些东西来？
- In our house? - Yeah.
- 这房子？ - 对
Uh... our couch,
嗯 那沙发
our bed,
那床
Benny's parents' dresser.
本尼父母给她的五斗柜
All your stuff.
什么都搬来
Yes. Exactly.
对 没错
That makes sense.
果然
You're like a fully fledged adult now.
你现在真的长大了
Guys, how long has it been since, like, we've hung out?
大伙儿 我们有多久没聚了？
I'm just sort of like...
见面只能尴尬来句...
Hi.
你好
Is it three years since we graduated?
我们毕业有三年了吧？
- Four, I think. - Oh, my God, is it four years?
- 四年了吧 - 哦 都四年了吗
Yeah.
是啊
Time really does fly.
时光飞逝啊
时光真飞逝啊
But not for me or Agnes probably,
不过 对我和安尼丝大概不算
since we're still here, still at the school.
我们还待在学校里
You're still at your same house.
你还待在那房子里
That little house.
那破房子里
But time probably flies for the three of you who left.
就你们三个走出去的会觉得飞逝
- New York. - Yeah, yeah. New York.
- 去纽约啦 - 嗯 对 纽约
Wow.
哦
Good for you.
替你高兴
Um, but it's a trip being back.
嗯 回来这趟感触挺深
I drove past the campus on my way to Agnes',
去安尼丝家路上路过学校
and I just got, like, full body chills when I saw the library.
见到图书馆就起鸡皮疙瘩
The library. Lydie, no. please.
那图书馆 利迪 别提了
You know what I mean?
你懂吧
I have, like, deeply ingrained stress from that place.
那地方给我留着很深的压力印记
Yeah, Grad school was wild. I honestly feel like
对 在研究院那会儿真太狠了
I worked on that thesis for like, a decade.
我写那论文跟长征一样
Yeah. This one time, um...on the third floor in a private room,
可不是嘛 有次我在图书馆自习室
I almost paper cut my face open with my copy of Little Dorrit
差点想用《小杜丽》那书
【译注 《小杜丽》：狄更斯（英）刻画阶级与贫困的辛辣作品】
just so I could go to the hospital and have a good night's sleep.
把脸划破 好去医院里睡个安稳觉
I didn't do it, but I thought about it.
没真做 但闪过那念头
Yeah, sometimes I have nightmares
嗯 有时我做噩梦
where my thesis is like all blank pages, and then I eat the pages.
梦到我论文全变白纸 我还把它吃了
Oh, my God, that's so sad.
天呐 那好可悲
Yeah. It is really sad, huh.
是啊 可不是嘛 真的挺可悲的
So, Agnes, it was really that easy for you?
那么 安尼丝 你就过得顺风顺水了？
No story? Nothing to share?
不想谈谈什么事情吗？
Well, it's not Agnes' fault that Decker liked her best.
那事儿可不是安尼丝的错 是德克尔太粘她
No, it wasn't her fault,  but, um, it pissed me off.
对 不是她的错 说来我都生气
This fish is amazing. What's... what's in it?
这鱼做的不错 里面放了什么
Fish.
鱼啊
Uh... well, how is it, you two?
你们俩近况如何？
You're the teachers now.
都是老师了
I am still part time,
我还没有转正
but I think I'm gonna teach a class next semester...
不过下学期会让我带一门课吧
which they haven't said is what's gonna happen, but it could.
还没正式说 但挺有戏
- Yeah, it could. - No. It will.
- 是啊 挺有戏 - 不 是一定会
Yeah. Yes. It, it will.
对 对 一定会
Well, we have news in the English department.
我们英语系这边还有新情况
Agnes? Agnes has big news.
安尼丝 该你的大新闻了
Bathroom. Sorry.
去下洗手间 抱歉
Agnes is now a full-time teacher. She took Wilkinson's spot.
安尼丝已转正 占了威尔金森留的位置
Filled the spot.
是接手了 那位置
Agnes is like super young to be full-time faculty.
安尼丝真厉害 这么年轻就转正了
Yeah, she's like the youngest in fifty years, that bitch.
对 五十年来最年轻的 靠腿上位的
I'm kidding.
开玩笑啦
There's a bone.
没去干净
What?
什么？
In the fish.
鱼刺没去干净
【译注 西餐通常会把鱼刺和骨头去除后上桌】
There's, like, a bone in the fish that you served me.
你这鱼没剔干净 里面还有根鱼刺
Sorry.
抱歉
No, it's... it's fine.
没事 没事
It's just like maybe you should, like,
下次你招待客人
debone it a little bit better before you serve it to people.
把鱼刺处理好 注意点礼数
Hello, my baby.
你好呀 我的猫宝贝
Oh, you're a baby.
我的猫宝贝
I love you. I love you.
妈妈爱你 妈妈爱你
Oh, you wanna get down?
噢 要下去吗？
Okay. I'll put you down.
好 把你放下去
You leave the house, right?
你会走出这房子吧？
Yeah. I leave the house.
嗯 天天走出啊
I go to work. I have a job, Lydie.
得去上班 我有工作的 利迪
But...
但...
you're still in the same office.
你还待在那间办公室里啊
Yes.
的确
Agnes, you said that you were gonna switch.
安尼丝 你说过你会换办公室的
Well, I...I didn't wanna have to explain why it's weird for me to be in that office.
我 我可不想被迫解释为什么换
Maybe you should say there's mold or something.
编个理由 说墙发霉之类的
Maybe.
也许吧
Do you want me to call them and say there's a dead animal in the wall?
该死 要我举报说墙里有死动物发臭吗？
You are an angel from heaven, but no.
你真是大好人 但不用
It's like, I just got the job.
我刚转正
I don't even know if I should have the job.
我都不知道我配不配得上这位子
Agnes.
安尼丝 别这样
I don't wanna complain about my office,
我不想嫌我的办公室
which is technically huge, and there's a lot of light,
空间大 采光又好
and I can see why he liked it.
我能明白他为什么喜欢这间
Anyways, yes, I leave the house.
总之 是的 我决定走出去这房子
Agnes...
安尼丝...
don't...
别...
die.
去死
I'm not gonna die.
我不会死的
If I was gonna kill myself,
要真打算自尽
I would have done it like last year...
我早在去年做了
or the year before.
或者在前年
Ugh. Or, like, definitely the year before.
呃 肯定在前年
Agnes.
安尼丝 别
No. I'm not gonna die.
我不会死的
Let me return the sentiment.
那我也回敬你一句
You please don't die.
你也别想着去死
Lydie...
利迪...
You're having a little baby.
你怀了个小宝宝
I know.
对
You're gonna take such good care of your little baby.
你会把宝宝照顾得很好
I won't die.
我不会死的
Please don't die.
求你别死
No, you please don't die.
不 我求你
Do you wanna say hello?
想跟宝宝打个招呼吗？
Hi.
嗨
I'm Agnes.
我是安尼丝
I'm your mommy.
我是你妈咪
Lydie and Fran may tell you otherwise, but heed my words.
利迪和弗兰可能会有别的说法 但听我说
- I'm your mother. - Agnes!
- 我是你妈 - 安尼丝！
- Do it properly. - Yeah. All right.
- 别闹 正经点 - 好 好吧
Hi. I'm Agnes.
嗨 我是安尼丝
I'm not your mommy.
我不是你妈咪
I am your mommy.
我就是你妈咪
Oh, for goodness sake.
哎 真受不了你
I felt it kick.
我觉得宝宝踢我了
No, you didn't.
没有 你没有
Are you gonna... Thank you.
那包...多谢
Don't go.
别走
Hey.
来
I'll see you soon.
我很快就来看你
When?
什么时候？
Come to New York.
来纽约吧
I've got an extra bed.
我有空床
Tell Fran that I hate them.
跟弗兰说我讨厌TA
【译注 TA为中性代词】
No.
才不
No, I don't hate them.
好吧 其实不讨厌TA
I know, babe.
我知道 宝贝
- Love you. - Love you.
- 爱你 - 也爱你
Um, no.
哦 等下
Come soon.
快点回来哦
Not because of, like,
不是因为...
not because I'm gonna kill myself, but just...
不是因为我要去死之类的 只是...
Just...
只是...
don't wait so long to come back.
别拖那么久才回来
Okay.
好的
好
那桩噩事的时光
Fuck!
靠！
What is happening?
怎么回事？
- What's happening? - Oh, my God!
- 到底怎么了？ - 靠！天呐！
I hate school!
我受够学校了！
School fucking sucks!
学校真把人逼疯了！
My brain feels like it's on fire.
我脑袋像着了火
Like I'm gonna fucking die!
像快要死了一样！
I just realized, babe,
我才发现 宝贝
no one gives a fuck about Ted Hughes.
没人会在乎泰德·休斯
【译注 泰德·休斯：英国诗人 以强烈自然意象和原始神话力量著称】
No, everyone cares about Ted Hughes.
不对 大家都挺在乎泰德·休斯的
No, no, no. I can't believe this.
不 不 不 我不相信
I spent two years writing about a guy.
我花了两年研究那男人
I don't even fuck guys with my eyes open anymore.
现在和男人上床我都不睁眼
I just close my eyes and imagine women.
只想闭眼想女人
Do you wanna talk about that?
要展开说说吗？
About what?
说什么？
Nothing.
没什么
Okay, I'm here. Sorry, I'm here.
好了 我来了 抱歉 来晚了
Did we do it?
都写完了吗？
Barely.
勉强
- Devin? - Yes, I did.
- 德文 你呢？ - 我做完了
I am so sorry. I don't really procrastinate,
抱歉各位 我平时不爱拖延
so this wasn't like a whole thing for me.
不是故意抢先的
That's okay.
没事的
Keep showing off, it'll get you places.
别太谦虚 真金藏不住的
Lydie.
利迪
I'm Lydie.
我在这儿
Did you finish?
你写好了吗？
Uh, yeah, um...
呃 是的 嗯...
Yeah, but the thing is,
好吧 是这样的
like, don't be mad. I did finish it.
别生气 确实写完了
The last page is, like, a copy and paste extract of...
只是最后一页是从...
"Slouching Towards Bethlehem" that I didn't write.
从《向伯利恒跋涉》复制来的 不是我写的
【译注 《向伯利恒跋涉》：琼·狄迪恩（美）散文 描绘60年代旧金山嬉皮与反文化】
- Yates or Didion? - Didion.
- 抄耶茨还是狄迪恩？ - 是狄迪恩
【译注 耶茨：指关注家庭生活的小说家理查德·耶茨（美）】
Always Didion.
当然是狄迪恩
Uh... Hey, you know what?
嗯...你看
I'm supposed to be your mentor, helper, whatever.
我是你的导师 帮手 之类的
I'm just here to make sure it happens.
来这是帮你按时交论文的
I did mine.
我的写完了
Okay. Good. That's... that's great, Natasha.
行 好 不错 娜塔莎
Lydie, you think you can finish by Wednesday?
利迪 周三前能搞定吗？
Get me your draft minus the Joan by then?
去掉狄迪恩的稿子给我
Yeah, again...
嗯 行吧
Sorry about that.
抱歉打断
Are you gonna read mine?
要看我的吗？
Of course. That's my job.
要啊 职责所在嘛
Are you gonna ask Agnes if she did hers?
你还要问安尼丝她交了吗？
Yeah.
要
Agnes...
安尼丝...
How'd yours go?
进展如何？
Fine. I did it.
挺好 做完了
Can't wait to read.
等不及想看了
But you're gonna read mine too though, right?
你也会想看我那份吧？
Yes.
会的
【译注 《反对阐释》：苏珊·桑塔格（美）散文 批判过度理论化 主张直接感受艺术】
（《反对阐释》）
Why am I still working on this?
我怎么还在写这东西？
Because you didn't finish it.
因为你还没写完
No offense.
别介意
Stop bragging.
别显摆了
I'm not bragging.
我又没显摆
Your legs are on the wall.
你腿翘在墙上呢
So?
那又怎样？
Well, if I'd finished it,
要是我也写完了
my legs would be on the wall too,
我腿也会翘上墙的
but I haven't.
可我还没写完
So, my legs aren't on the wall.
所以我没翘着
Okay. I will take them down.
行 我把腿放下
（教授 普雷斯顿·德克尔：这写得真出类拔萃）
What?
又怎么了？
You should fuck him.
你应该跟他上床
I don't wanna fuck him.
我不想跟他上床
- Really? - Yes.
- 真的？ - 真的
Well, if you don't wanna fuck him, definitely don't fuck him.
那如果你不想 就千万别做
I won't.
不会的
I think he wants to fuck you.
我觉得他想上你
Really?
真的？
Yeah.
嗯
Well, that sucks.
哦 这可不妙
Why?
怎么了？
Do you think that's why he's telling me I'm smart?
他老夸我聪明是图这个吗？
No, I think he's telling you you're smart because you're really smart.
不 我觉得他夸你因为你真很聪明
Okay.
好
What would you say though...
你会怎么回他...
if he asked you to fuck him?
他开口要你跟他睡？
I would say no.
我会说不的
I would be upset if he asked.
他要开口 我会生气的
I get that.
懂了
I would say no...
我会当面说 不...
but thank you.
不过 谢谢你
（教授 普雷斯顿·德克尔 英语系）
Come on in.
请进
Hi.
嗨
Agnes, hi.
安尼丝 你好
Thanks for meeting with me.
谢谢你见我
也谢谢你来见我
Are you working on something?
手头挺忙的？
I mean...
我是说...
No. Not, not...
没有 没什么
not really.
没什么特别的
Well, now you have to tell me.
好吧 你得交代清楚
Why?
为什么？
Because now I know too much.
因为我已经知道不少了
Uh, yeah, okay. Um...
嗯 行 好吧
I'm writing a book.
我在写本书
- A book? - A book.
- 书？ - 嗯
A long book?
大部头吗？
- Medium. - Good.
- 中等长度 - 挺好
Why?
为啥？
Well, long is like... okay, we get it.
长篇就那样 说得太透
Right. And short is like...
对 短篇则...
Why did you even write a book?
像雾里看花
Yeah, well, even though this is medium...
嗯 我写的这中篇则...
- The perfect length. - Yeah.
- 正好合适 - 嗯
I have to say it is horrible, and every time I look at it, I wanna kill myself.
这书烂透了 看见它我都想上吊
Well, there actually have to be books like that
就需要坏书来衬托
so that we can distinguish which books are really the good books.
好书才能更显珍贵
Yes.
对
I'm doing a public service by writing a shit book.
这破书也算是为社会做贡献了
Well,
好吧
if it helps at all,
这样安慰你吧
I liked your first novel.
我挺喜欢你第一本小说的
I liked how fucked up it was and...
它烂得独特
how it made me feel like there's a reason,
让我觉得活着有意义
even if I can't see it, that I'm alive.
哪怕我看不清那理由
And it didn't feel like fiction,
读起来不像小说
which I think is a compliment in this case.
不是那种做作的虚构
And...I think about it all the time when I'm doing other stuff,
我 我做别的事时常想起它
like eating ice cream or looking out the window.
吃冰淇时 望窗外时
Thank you.
谢谢你
也谢谢你
Okay, uh...
好...
Enough about me.
别光说我了
I read your thesis.
你的论文我看完了
You read it really fast.
看得挺快的
Yeah, well, I, uh...
是啊 嗯...
to be honest, I couldn't put it down.
真的爱不释手
Someone glue your hands to it?
谁把你手粘上面了吗？
What?
啥？
Oh...
噢
I'm sorry. Makes basically no sense.
抱歉 玩笑开得有点莫名
No, it does.
不 挺有趣的
Yeah.
嗯
- Anyway, so, uh... - Yeah.
- 总之... - 嗯
This whole section from page three through seven,
从第三页到第七页这段
I find to be absolutely just...
简直
extraordinary.
出类拔萃
Really.
真的
Sorry.
抱歉
Sorry, my ex is a prosecutor, which...
抱歉 我前妻是个检察官 这就...
Oh, wow, the law.
哇 搞法律的
Yeah. My ex- wife...
对 我前妻...
loves the law.
特爱法律
She's in court, my kid's sick. I have to...
她在出庭 我孩子病了 我得...
I've gotta run.
我得赶紧走了
- Fuck, sorry. - Oh, that's okay.
- 该死 抱歉 - 没事的
You should have my full attention, and frankly, this paper deserves that.
你配得上我全部注意力 这论文也是
- We can reschedule for later. - Yeah, that's fine.
- 我们改天再约 - 行 可以
All right, I gotta... I'll text you.
好 我得走了 回来给你发短信
- Okay. - I'll, uh...
- 好 - 我 呃...
Sorry I have to run like this.
抱歉这么仓促
- Oh, that's okay. - Oh, actually,
- 哦 没关系 - 哦 等下
you should look at this.
你得看看这个
I just got it.
我刚收到的
First edition To The Lighthouse.
《到灯塔去》初版
【译注 《到灯塔去》：伍尔夫（英）1927年所著意识流小说 讲家庭、记忆和时间】
Wow, wow. Thank you.
哇 谢谢
Yeah.
嗯
Can I touch it?
能摸摸吗？
- Yeah. - Okay.
- 当然 - 好
All right.
就这样
We are asked to reckon with the idea
思考一下
that taking his life, taking flight from the corporeal existence,
结束生命 从肉身飞走
【译注 莫里森（美）小说《所罗门之歌》 讲述黑人家庭的寻根与自由】
is perhaps for Milkman
对奶娃来说
a transcendence and not a tragedy.
是一种升华而非悲剧
Milkman feels he is returning to his ancestral home.
他感觉自由与回归
（教授 普雷斯顿·德克尔 英语系）
- Agnes. - Hi.
- 安尼丝 - 嗨
Great. Okay. Uh...
好 行 呃....
Thanks for coming last minute.
谢谢能临时赶来
Sorry, it's my house. hope that's okay.
抱歉约在我家 希望你不介意
Yeah, yeah, no problem.
嗯嗯 没事的
Don't worry, my...
别担心 我...
my kid's with my ex.
我孩子跟前妻在一起了
It's all good.
没关系的
- Uh, come on in. - Okay.
- 来 进来 - 嗯
Oh, do you mind taking your boots off?
哦 介意把鞋脱一下吗？
Oh, yeah. duh.
哦 对 我真笨
No.
别
- Sorry. - Don't be sorry.
- 抱歉 - 不用道歉
Do you have my thesis?
你带我的论文了吗？
Oh, yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
哦 有的 有的 带了
Your shoes are untied.
你鞋带开了
Ooh.
唔
Hey, I've been literally waiting with bated breath.
我等得心都痒死了
How did it go?
快说说
Agnes, are you okay?
安尼丝 你没事吧？
What happened?
发生什么事了？
I don't know.
说不上来
My pants are broken.
裤子被弄坏了
And then we started kissing.
然后我们开始接吻
And I thought, we're kissing.
我心想 我们竟然在接吻
I was thinking we were kissing the whole time,
我一直在想
like in a bad way
这种接吻很糟
where you aren't having a good time,
一点也不享受
and it's just like someone's mouth.
就像被别人嘴顶着
And then I said, "I don't really think I'm ready to be kissing.
我跟他说 “我还没准备好亲...
I just got out of a thing."
我刚结束一段恋情”
Which is something I made up.
这是当时瞎编的
It's okay to lie about that.
找个借口是对的
And then he said, "That's okay."
他回了句 “没事”
"We can just sit on the couch and watch a movie."
“在沙发上一起看个电影吧”
So he started playing something.
他播了个片子
It was animated, which I thought was weird.
是动画片 起初觉得怪怪的
But then I remembered he has a kid,
但一想他还有个孩子
so that made it less weird.
就不那么怪了
Then he started putting his hand on my pants,
然后他把手伸到我裤裆上
and I was kinda moving it away.
我想推开
But he kept moving it back to my pants,
他老是伸回来
and then he started putting his hand down my pants, like,
最后直接把手伸到我裤子里
in between the pants and my underwear.
就隔着层内裤
And I was kinda squirming my body like...
我不断扭身挣扎
he was...
他的...
his fingers were really strong and hard, like, in the bad way.
他的手指粗暴使劲
Like, it was too hard.
太用力了
Maybe it would've felt good if I wanted his fingers to be doing that.
要是我同意 可能会享受
But you didn't want that.
但你不同意
No, I didn't.
不 根本不同意
And then, I pulled his hand out because...
然后我拽出他的手 因为...
it didn't feel good,
因为真不舒服
and it actually hurt, kinda.
甚至还疼
And then I started kissing him
然后我去吻他
because I thought,
我心想
"Well, if we have to be doing something,"
得做点什么
"I'd rather it be kissing than his fingers down there."
宁可接吻也不想被摸
And then I don't remember.
之后一片空白
And then at some point, his hand was back in my underwear.
突然间 他又把手伸进来了
But under the underwear now.
但这次是内裤里面
And I was trying to move it away again.
我不断拽他的手
Sounds like you were trying to move it away a lot.
听上去你一直在想办法
Yeah. That's what I kept thinking.
嗯 一直在想
Like, one more time and he won't move it back
心想 只要再制止他一次
because it's so obvious I'm moving it away.
他就会明白
But he kept moving it back.
但他还不断地把手伸回来
And then...
然后...
he was pulling down my pants. well, he was trying to pull them down,
他开始脱我裤子 用力扯
but they have a button.
但没解扣子
So he was pulling, pulling.
他就一直扯啊扯
And I was pulling them back up.
我就往回拽
And then they were halfway down.
最后裤子被扯到大腿间
And I felt something go in, like, in me,
然后感觉有什么就 就进来了
and my spine got cold.
我毛骨悚然
And I reached down to feel it and...
我伸手去摸...
It was...
发现...
It was him... you know?
是他的...懂吧
And then I jumped up and...
然后我跳起来
I sat on the side of the couch.
坐到沙发另一头
I don't know how long.
不知道发呆了多久
And I looked at his face once,
只敢瞥他一眼
and it was, like, scared.
他居然 害怕了
- His face was scared? - Yes.
- 他看起来害怕？ - 是
And then I just got up kinda slowly,
然后我慢慢起身
and I grabbed my boots,
拿上鞋
and I drove home,
开车回家
and now I'm here.
然后就在这儿了
That sounds like...
你说的就是...
that.
那种事
That is...
就是...
that's the thing.
那种事
I'm really, really sorry.
我真的 真的很心痛
I never know if I'm supposed to get fully naked.
这检查是不是得一丝不挂？
- Like in the gown? - Yeah.
- 只穿这病号服吗？ - 嗯
- Are you naked right now? - Yes.
- 你现在光着了吗？ - 是的
Dude, I don't think you're supposed to be naked.
小宝 你不该光着啊
Hi. You're Agnes?
你好 是安尼丝吧？
- Yeah, hi. - I'm doctor Evans.
- 嗯 你好 - 我是埃文斯医生
You were sexually assaulted?
被人性侵了？
Uh, yeah.
呃 是的
Do you feel safe now?
现在感觉安全吗？
Sorry, before... uh, we do that,
抱歉 开始前 额...我得说
I just want you to know that I'm fully naked.
我可光着呢
- What? - Under the robe. Is that okay?
- 啥？ - 是病号服下面光着 行吗？
Yeah. That's fine.
可以 没问题
- Do you mind? - Yeah, sure.
- 介意让下吗？ - 好 行
So, when did this happen?
好 什么时候的事儿？
The thing?
那件事？
The assault.
你受害
Last night.
昨天晚上
Last evening.
昨天下午
Yesterday evening.
昨天傍晚
- And have you showered? - I took a bath.
- 事后有洗澡吗？ - 洗了
So it's usually best to go to the emergency room
这种事最好...
right after something like this happens.
事发后马上来急诊
Oh, okay. I will definitely keep that in mind for the next time.
行 下回记住了
Well, that's when we would use a sexual assault forensic evidence kit.
在急诊室会用性侵取证包
Oh, okay. I feel like you just need to...tonally shift away from the tone
打断下 麻烦您换个说法
you're taking right now.
换个语气
Like, we just need a tonal shift.
温和点那种
Just wanna make sure he didn't give me anything, like, vaginally or yeah.
就想检查有没有被传到什么 通过阴道的那种
Did your attacker ejaculate in you?
施暴者在你体内射精了吗？
Um, well, I wouldn't call him my attacker.
额 我不太想叫他施暴者
It wasn't like, bah!
不是 啪 那种
But you were raped.
你可被强奸了啊
- Whoa. - Yeah. And well put.
- 哎呦喂 - 是 无言以对
I know this is hard to talk about.
我理解你说不出口
It doesn't feel that you know that.
不像是您真理解了啊
These questions are protocol.
没办法 得按流程里的问
Yeah, you're asking them in a really freaky way.
嗯 但您问TA的方式真尖锐啊
Calm down, ma'am.
冷静点 女士
- Oh, she's calm. - I'm calm.
- 她很冷静 - 我可冷了
You can finish your questions.
继续问吧
Did he ejaculate in you?
他有没有在你体内射精？
Horrible word.
真能问啊
No, the actual him being inside me part wasn't that long, it was like...
没 他进来的时间不长 就像...
- that long. - Okay.
- 那几下 - 好
So, we'll do a blood test to check you for pregnancy
接下来抽个血 查怀孕
and sexually transmitted infections,
查性病感染
and then we'll do a cervix culture.
再来个宫颈培养
- Yum. - Excuse me?
- 好享受啊 - 说啥？
She said yum.
她说好享受啊
I'll be right back, and we can get started.
我马上回来 马上开始
- Agnes? - Mhmm.
- 安尼丝 - 嗯哼
He's leaving.
他走了
Who?
谁？
Decker's transferring.
德克尔搬走了
He got a job in New York. Upstate.
他在纽约上州找了个工作
He's leaving.
他走了
Fuck.
靠
What the fuck?
什么鬼？
Is this good?
是好事吗？
No.
不是
Maybe. I don't know.
也许 说不准
Did he say anything about this?
他跟你提过要走吗？
No.
没
And yesterday his desk was, like, really cluttered.
昨天他桌上和平常一样乱
Like he wasn't packed or anything.
不像要搬家的样子
So he's running.
所以他跑路了
Fuck.
挨千刀的
- Hi, I'm... - Agnes.
- 你好 我是... - 是安尼丝吧
Hi, I'm Elizabeth. This is Claire.
你好 我叫伊丽莎白 这位是克莱尔
- Hi, Agnes. I'm Claire. - Hi.
- 你好 我是克莱尔 - 幸会
Do you mind coming back with us?
能麻烦你跟我们来一下吗？
Sure.
行
We are so sorry to hear this happened to you.
很抱歉发生了这种事
We are taking this
我们会...
really seriously.
认真严肃处理的
Are you gonna do anything?
怎么处理？
We would begin an investigation.
我们会展开调查
But as you may have heard,
只是你可能听说了
he sent in his letter of resignation yesterday at...
他昨天递交了辞呈 在...
4:18 p.m.
昨天下午4:18分
And you reported this today at 8:42 am.
而你是在今天早上8:42分才报告的
Okay.
好
Unfortunately, he's no longer under our employ.
遗憾地是 他已经离职
So we can't take the measures that we would normally take
因此无法实施
such as suspending him or letting him go or...
停职 解雇之类的处分
things of that nature.
无能为力
These things are really hard,
这件事真不好办
and the University is unfortunately unable
很遗憾大学这边
to take any kind of responsibility.
无法承担任何责任
But he was my advisor.
可他是我的导师啊
Former advisor.
前任 导师
You have the option of going to the police station and reporting this
建议你去警局报案
and issuing an arrest warrant.
让他们发逮捕令
We know what you're going through.
我们对此感同身受
We are women.
我们也是女性
What?
什么？
We are women.
我们也是女性
Hi.
嘿
嗨
You're my neighbor, right?
你是我邻居吧？
Yeah, I live here.
嗯 我住这儿
What's your name?
你叫什么？
Oh, uh, Gavin.
哦 呃 盖文
Gavin, nice to meet you.
盖文 幸会
- You too. - I'm Agnes.
- 彼此彼此 - 我是安尼丝
Lamb of God.
圣经里的羔羊
【译注 开玩笑说安尼丝是耶稣化身】
- What? - That's nothing.
- 什么？ - 算了
It's all good, I'm just, uh...
没什么 我就是 呃...
What are you up to this fine evening?
你今晚忙啥？
Oh, I was wondering, do you have, like, stuff that makes a fire?
呃 你有能点火的东西吗？
Oh, um...
哦 呃...
Matches?
火柴吗？
No, like a liquid. Is that a thing?
不是 要那种助燃液 有吧
Oh, yes.
有的
- Lighter fluid. - Yes. Do you have that?
- 烧烤助燃油 - 对 有吗？
Yes.
有
Why do you need it?
用来干嘛？
Um, my friends and I, we're gonna make, like, hot dogs.
呃 我跟一帮朋友要做烤肠
Oh, hot dog sounds good.
哦 我也喜欢吃烤肠
Oh, I'm sorry, we only bought two hot dogs.
抱歉 只买了两根
Oh, no, that's no problem, I'm...I have dinner plans with my mom.
哦 不 没关系 我...我跟我妈吃
That's not true.
不是的
I'm sorry, I just wanted to close myself off
我怕被拒
from the possibility of being rejected.
才装作有事的
That's no problem.
没事
- I'll get the lighter fluid. - Okay.
- 我去拿助燃油 - 好
Do you wanna come inside while I look?
屋里暖和 进来坐坐？
Uh, no, sorry. Can I wait outside?
算了 想在这儿等 行吗？
Yeah. Don't worry about it. Um, I'll be back soon.
行 没问题 我马上给你
This should do the trick.
这该够用
Great, thanks.
太好了 谢谢
And so do I just pour this on the thing I want to be on fire?
倒在要烧的东西上 就行了吧？
On the barbecue?
烧什么 烧烤吗？
Yes.
对
Uh, yeah, don't put too much of it on there.
呃 嗯 别倒太多
Okay.
好
Do you... do you want my help?
要 要我帮忙吗？
No.
不用
Thank you...
谢谢你...
Gavin.
是盖文
Gavin. Yes. Thank you, definitely, Gavin.
对 盖文 真谢谢你 盖文
Uh, don't you live over there?
你不是住那边吗？
Ha! Yup, I... yup, definitely. Oops.
啥 哦 对 确实是 哈哈
（《乔凡尼的房间》）
【译注 《乔凡尼的房间》：詹姆斯·鲍德温（美）所著小说 聚焦同性恋身份与孤独】
Why do you have that?
从哪儿弄的？
I got it from the neighbor.
找邻居要的
Why?
干嘛要？
It's definitely not, like, a good or normal train of thought.
肯定不是正常人会有的想法
Okay.
好
I think I was gonna light Decker's office on fire.
我本来想把德克尔办公室烧掉
Okay...
好
Do you still wanna do it?
你真想这么做吗
I don't know.
没想好
I will do it.
那我来做
That's really nice.
你真好
But no.
但不用
No, seriously. If you need someone to burn his office down,
认真说 要是你想烧他办公室
but you don't wanna do it yourself, I will do it.
又不想自己去 我替你做
No, I don't even want him to die.
不 我甚至不想咒他死
I do.
我想
I don't want him to die.
我不想他死
Well, if you change your mind...
好吧 改主意了就告诉我
Thanks.
谢谢
Maybe we could burn something smaller,
也许一起烧点小的
like his hair or his pens or something.
他头发或他笔之类的
I'll think about that.
我会考虑的
Okay.
好
I have to make hot dogs.
哎 还得去做烤肠
Oh, why?
为嘛？
I told the neighbor, it's like this whole big lie. I'm stuck in a lie.
我跟邻居编了大谎 不烤心里过不去
Okay. I will do it.
好 我来做
I'm sorry.
对不起
No, it's fine. I was gonna, like, kill a man, so this is much easier.
没事 我本想砍个人 相比这小菜一碟
Do we have hot dogs?
家里有烤肠吗？
I don't know.
不知道
Hi.
嗨
Okay. I'm going to get coffee.
好 我要去买咖啡
Do you want me to pick you up?
我能抱你吗？
Well, fuck.
哦 天呐
This is really nice.
太美好了
I guess um...
我想...
Yup. I love you.
对 我爱你
You wanna come get coffee?
愿意陪我买咖啡吗？
Salmon.
三文鱼罐头？
All right, you're picky, an excellent quality.
好吧 挺挑食的 有品位
Tuna.
金枪鱼的？
Maybe you're just smelling the can.
可能隔着罐头闻不出来
There's tuna inside.
里面是金枪鱼
All right, one of each.
好 各买一罐
Hey.
嗨
Is this all for you today?
就这些吗？
Yes, thank you.
是的 麻烦了
Did you bring a cat into the grocery store?
你带猫进来了吗？
No.
没有啦
Yes, you did.
就有
What did you say?
信号不好 说啥？
You're lying.
你骗人
No, I'm not.
不 才没呢
Here's your cat food.
您的猫粮 谢谢惠顾
We ran out of coffee.
咖啡没了
I got some.
我买了
I got a cat.
我捡了只猫
Whatever you need.
挺你啦
善问 恶问与自问的时光
Thank you for being here and completing your summons.
谢谢大家来履行陪审员传召
For those of you who haven't done this and don't know what to expect,
还没填的 不清楚流程的
please come up and get a questionnaire.
请上前来领问卷表
Fill it out and return it to us completed.
填好交回来
We have little pencils if you need a little pencil.
要用笔的话 请来拿
（陪审员资格问卷表 姓名：安尼丝·沃德 年龄：28岁）
【译注 自我认同性别流动 非二元 偏女性】
The following jurors are dismissed.
以下人员免除陪审义务
Juror one, three, five,
陪审员 1号 3号 5号
seven, eight,
7号 8号
30, 32,
30号 32号
39, 25,
39号 25号
42, 43,
42号 43号
49, 59.
49号 59号
You are dismissed.
你们免除义务
Thank you. You can go.
谢谢 你们可以离庭了
And do you think, Mrs. Fuller, based on that definition,
富勒女士 通过刚才讲解
you understand the meaning of beyond a reasonable doubt?
您明白“排除合理怀疑”意思吗？
【译注 证据使陪审员对被告有罪的怀疑不再合理】
Yes.
明白
That to be convinced beyond a shadow of a doubt,
要达到不怀疑的标准
you must have been there and seen the crime with your own eyes?
在案发时非得亲眼见到吗？
Yes. I understand.
不用 明白
And do the rest of you feel
大家都能以
- you can apply that idea, beyond a reasonable doubt, to this case? - Mhmm
- “排除合理怀疑”作为评判依据吗？ - 是
How many of you have children?
有多少人是父母？
Uh, Mr. Woguard. You have a child?
沃瓜德先生 有孩子？
Uh, yes. Soph just turned four.
嗯 是 索菲刚满四岁
Say you and your daughter were at the park
假设您女儿在公园
and she's playing on the monkey bars.
玩攀爬架
And you turned your back for a few minutes,
您有几分钟没看她
and then she runs over to you with a broken arm.
她跑过来说胳膊伤了
What would you think happened?
您怎么判断？
She fell off the monkey bars and broke her arm.
她从攀爬架上掉下来摔的
Yes, so that's an example of circumstantial evidence.
对 这就是间接证据的例子
That's what you can reasonably infer based on the facts that you have.
根据事实可以做出的合理推断
Does this make sense, Mr. Woguard?
沃瓜德先生 能明白吗
Yes.
明白
And if instead another child ran over to you
要是有其他孩子跑来告诉您
and told you he saw her fall off the monkey bars,
说看见她怎么摔的
that's direct testimony because someone witnessed it.
有人目击 这就是直接证词
Does everybody understand that difference,
大家能明白
between circumstantial evidence and direct testimony?
间接证据和直接证词的区别吗？
Mhmm.
能
Without direct testimony,
没有直接证词
we cannot be positively certain a crime has been committed.
就不能肯定犯罪一定发生
As the prosecution,
作为检方
I must prove the defendant's guilt beyond a reasonable doubt.
我得把罪证明到排除合理怀疑
Meaning, that there is no other reasonable explanation
即 从现有的证据中
that can come from evidence presented.
不存在其他合理解释
If any of you have been victims of a crime,
谁是犯罪受害者
please raise your hand.
请举手
Uh, Mr. Faber, what was the crime?
费伯先生 您遭遇了什么？
Uh, I was robbed. At gunpoint.
我被抢劫了 持枪的
Do you have any reason to believe
您认为
that experience would make you unable to serve
那次遭遇会妨碍您
as an impartial juror on this trial?
担任此庭公正陪审员吗？
No.
不会
Miss Ward.
沃德小姐
What?
什么？
When I asked who has been a victim of a crime,
刚问到受害者时
did you raise your hand?
您举手了吧？
No, I realized I shouldn't share it. So...
不是的 我不能讲这件事 就...
You're unable to share the crime?
不能讲受害经历？
It is frankly my worst nightmare to have to tell this whole room of strangers
这样说吧 大庭广众说出来那事儿
about the thing that happened to me.
是我最害怕的
So...
所以...
that is the reasoning as to why I did not decide
所以我才把手
to continue having my hand raised.
又放下来了
Thank you.
见谅
Do you think the crime would make you unable to serve
那次遭遇会妨碍您
as an impartial juror on this case?
担任此庭公正陪审员吗？
That is a good question, and one I've been thinking about.
问得好 我一直在想这个
Have you come to any conclusions?
想出结论了吗？
You know, I think I would be better not being on the jury
我觉得 退出陪审团更合适
and instead would do better fulfilling a different civic role.
做别的事情为社会做贡献
And what kind of civic role do you have in mind?
什么别的事情？
So, thank you for asking. I am actually a professor,
谢谢你问 我是个教授
part-time, hopefully soon full-time,
还没转正 期待早日实现
which, teaching is important work.
教书很重要
I think teaching is important.
教学是很有意义的
Some would say that a teacher makes an ideal juror.
有人说教师是最合适的陪审员
Absolutely not, no.
才不是呢 不
On your questionnaire, you wrote...
你的问卷表上写着...
Oh, no, no.
哦 别 别
I did not know that we would be reading those aloud, so.
我没想到会被当众念出来
"How would your friends describe you?"
“你朋友怎样形容你”
"Smart." Crossed out, then the word "tall."
“聪明”被划掉了 改成了个“高”
If the crime you were a victim of makes you biased, we will dismiss you.
要是那遭遇让你有偏见 就会免除你
Can I get in trouble for telling you?
说了不会惹上事吧？
Why would you get in trouble if you were the victim?
你是受害者 怎会有事？
I don't know.
我不知道
The law makes no sense in my opinion.
法律有很多不讲理的地方
I...
那...
I haven't said it out loud actually before.
那事我从未公开说过
Well, that's okay.
没关系的
Did you go to the police?
你报警了吗？
No.
没有
All I had was a button,
物证只有个扣子
and I don't want him to go to jail.
我也不想见他坐牢
Why is that?
为什么？
He has a kid.
他有个孩子
I want him to stop being someone who does that.
我希望给他个机会改过
And if he went to jail,
要是进了监狱
he'd just be someone who does that, who's now in jail.
他就永远被定义成那种人了
Your honor, may I approach the bench?
法官阁下 我可以上前吗？
Agnes Ward, you are excused.
安尼丝·沃德 获准离庭
I'm sorry.
抱歉
Clerk, you may call the next juror.
书记员 请传下一位陪审员
Okay. We'll now call up...
好 现在叫...
Rex Haberman.
雷克斯·哈伯曼
Rex?
在吗？
暖心三明治的时光
Oh, my God.
天呐
Did you have a good time?
刚才满意吗？
What?
什么？
Did you like the sex we just had?
你满意刚才的那个吗？
Mhmm.
嗯嗯
Okay.
好
Good.
太好了
Thank you.
谢谢你
也谢谢你
Agnes, we've gotten incredibly positive feedback
安尼丝 你带的讨论课
from the students in your discussion section
学生反馈非常好
about your part-time contribution to this university.
作为兼职教师你很受欢迎
From current faculty, former faculty, it's just all glowing.
不管是现任教师 还是前任 都在夸你
- Former faculty? - Yes.
- 还有前任？ - 有
You've been called, let's see,
大家都这样形容你...
helpful,
乐于助人
supportive,
无微不至
extraordinary.
还有 出类拔萃
We know there's been talk about the open spot here
一直在讨论谁来接手
since Preston left, we haven't...
普雷斯顿·德克尔离职后的空位
well, we wanted to find the right fit for the program.
得找个最合适的接手人
And we are thrilled to finally offer you
很高兴 费尔波特这儿
a full-time teaching position here at Fairport.
终于要请你做全职教师了
Really?
真的？
Yes, yes.
真的 真的
The department voted unanimously.
系里一致同意的
Wow. I accept.
哇 我接受
Terrific.
太好了
You'll teach our introductory course, "The Twentieth Century Novel,"
你来教入门课 二十世纪小说
which you've led a few times,
你已经带过几回了
and you'll also create your own elective.
还可以自己开一门选修课
We would love for you to consider
我们很想请你
teaching a class on the art of the short story
开一门短篇小说赏析课
since we all read your thesis and frankly found that fascinating.
都读过你那论文 写得很吸引人
Okay.
行吧
Or if there's another course you'd rather teach, though.
想教别的也行
No, no, it's just I...
不 不是 只是...
I haven't looked at my thesis since I published it, but I will.
发表后我就没碰过它 但我会再看的
I can...I can look through it, and I will create a syllabus for you to look at.
看完后给你拟一份教学大纲
Wonderful.
太好了
We're thrilled to have you.
我们很高兴你能来任教
Thank you.
谢谢
Agnes, I have to tell you something.
安尼丝 跟你说件事
I am in love.
我坠入爱河了
- What? - Yeah! - What!
- 真的？ - 是呀 - 天呐
And like, super, super gay.
超级 超级女同的那种爱
Like, gayer than we thought.
远超咱们想象
Oh, wow.
哦 哇哦
Oh, my God. With that person?
天呐 是那位吗？
- Yeah. Fran. - Okay.
- 对 弗兰 - 好
- Yeah. - Wow.
- 对 - 厉害
Wow. Okay, are you so happy being gay and in love?
做女同又被爱 超幸福吧？
Oh, I'm like really, really happy being gay and in love.
幸福死了 做女同又被爱超棒
Oh, my God, you have to meet them!
天呐 你得见见TA！
Yeah, I totally do. I do.
好 我绝对想见
You...Oh, Lydie, you deserve to be in love all the time forever.
哦 利迪 你值得永远 永远被爱
Thank you, babe.
谢谢你 宝贝
Well, well... so I got the job.
对 对了 我拿到职位了
What?
什么？
I got the full-time position.
我刚转正
Oh, my God!
天呐
What? Agnes!
真假的？安尼丝
Yeah, well, it's, it's...not as good as being in love.
真的 但没坠入爱河那么棒
Yes it is. This is amazing.
才不是呢 这超棒的
This is great.
太好了
Agnes.
我的安尼丝
Yeah, no, it's good.
行吧 也挺棒
You really, really earned this, Agnes.
真的 真的是你应得的 安尼丝
（论文批注 出类拔萃）
And here is your office.
这就是你的办公室了
Let me know if you need anything,
有需要随时找我
if a light bulb goes out, anything like that.
像灯泡坏了这类 随时找我
- Thanks, Sophie. - Mm.
- 谢谢你 索菲 - 嗯
"And it struck me, as my automaton knees went up and down
“当我的身体像活塞般起伏时
that I simply did not know a thing about my darling's mind
我才发现对小尤物的内心一无所知
【译注 正在朗读《洛丽塔》第二部第32章】
and that quite possibly behind the awful, juvenile cliches...
也许她稚嫩的想法背后
there was in her a garden and a twilight and a palace gate,
有花园 暮色与城堡的大门
（《洛丽塔》）
dim and adorable regions which happened to be
那朦胧可爱的心境
lucidly and absolutely forbidden..."
却对我心门紧闭...”
Professor Ward.
沃德教授
Yes.
说
I'm sorry, but I personally found this book really disgusting.
抱歉 我觉得这书真很恶心
Well, Jeremy, there's a world in which that's a relief to hear.
听男人这么说真宽慰
How did you find the writing itself?
那文笔呢？
Well, that's the thing is I...I felt pissed off because I...
这 这就是矛盾的地方
really hated the stuff happening
我讨厌情节本身
but I really liked the sort of stuff he was saying.
但又喜欢他的文笔
- So I was pissed. - Mmm, okay.
- 又爱又恨 - 嗯 没事
Was anyone else feeling that way caught between the form,
谁还有同感
the presentation itself, and the content of that presentation?
被手法和内容搞得矛盾？
Uh, professor... that lady is back
呃 教授 那女士又来了
looking through the little window thing.
又从小窗往这儿看
She is persistent.
她很执着
Much like Humbert's desire to freeze Lolita in time.
像亨伯特想把洛丽塔永远锁在青春里
- Nice. - Okay. Let's read.
- 说得好 - 好 继续读
"For I often noticed that living as we did,
“我常常发现 我们俩生活在一个
she and I, in a world of total evil..."
完全邪恶的世界里”
- So... - Hi.
- 听说... - 嗨
Lydie got engaged.
利迪订婚了
Yeah.
嗯
When's the wedding?
什么时候办婚礼？
It's in the summer.
夏天办
- Do you like Fran? - Oh, yeah. Fran is nice.
- 你喜欢弗兰吗？ - 挺喜欢的
Reserved, kind of. Really tall.
有点腼腆 善良 个子还高
What's happening?
你想说什么？
So you got the job.
听说你转了正职
Yes.
是啊
I wanted the job.
我也想要这职位
Okay.
好
- Do you feel bad at all? - Yes.
- 就不觉得自己做错了吗？ - 有错
But, for other reasons, not because of this.
但不是我 是别人的
Okay, well, um...just because things come easy to you
对你来说顺风顺水
doesn't mean that you get to take things from people
不代表你能抢
who things don't come easy to.
别人难得的机会
Things don't come easy to me.
我活得可不轻松
Yes they do. Everyone likes you.
就轻松 大家都喜欢你
- You're smart, you're hot. - Thank you.
- 又聪明又性感 - 谢谢
Ew, not like that.
呃 是有魅力
Logan likes you, Devin likes you.
洛根喜欢你 德文喜欢你
Lydie likes you.
利迪喜欢你
Decker likes you.
德克尔也喜欢你
Well, you don't like me.
可你并不喜欢我
That's true.
还真是
You know, when I think about it,
仔细想来
I think Decker actually hated me.
德克尔其实恨我
You were his chosen one. That's a completely insane thing to say.
他最偏心的就是你 你竟敢这么说
No. Because when you like someone or, like,
不对 因为当你被喜欢
when you respect someone,
或被尊重时
there are some ways people treat you that are one way.
人们会尊重你的意愿
Respectful, and like,
尊重你的感受
you're a person who lives and breathes and thinks for them self.
把你当成有血有肉 有独立思考的人
And then some ways people treat you are not that way,
但也有不顾你感受的人
and they're bad.
而那很可恶
All right. Well, um, I fucked him...
好吧 我和他上过床
and, uh, he didn't even take the time
结果他连当面
to give me in-person notes on my thesis. So...
给我论文批注都懒得做 所以嘛
You fucked him?
你跟他睡过？
Yeah.
对
Did you want that?
是你同意的吗？
Want what?
同意什么？
Was it on purpose?
是你主动的吗？
Yes, it was on purpose.
主动的 咋了
We had, like, five minute sex. It was just okay. I've had better.
就五分钟 挺一般 我玩过更好的
We're closed. You can't park here.
我们打烊了 这儿不能停车
Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
糟了 糟了
Look, I'm sorry I yelled at you.
对不起 我不该冲你吼
My kid, Hank, gets these breathing attacks too, real bad sometimes.
我儿子汉克也会这样喘 有时很严重
I know you're scared,
我知道你在害怕
but you're off the road, you're in your car,
但你已离开车道了 在车里
and you're okay.
你很安全
I'm gonna breathe and you breathe with me. Okay?
我来带你呼吸 你跟我学 好吗？
You just follow.
跟上节奏
All right? You ready? In...
好 准备好 吸...
Out... two, three, four, five.
呼 二 三 四 五
In...
吸...
Out... two, three, four, five.
呼 二 三 四 五
In...
吸...
Out... two, three, four, five.
呼 二 三 四 五
In... two, three.
吸 二 三 四 五
Out... Two, three, four, five.
呼 二 三 四 五
I gotta be honest, I don't really breathe like that, but it feels good.
真心说 我平时不这么呼吸 但感觉不错
You doing okay?
还好吧？
Good for you.
干得好
You want a sandwich?
想吃个三明治吗？
I wanted to put tables out here, so,
我本想摆这儿几张桌子
people, you know, wouldn't sit on the ground.
至少有地方坐着吃
It's a good sandwich.
这三明治配得上好地方
You shouldn't eat a good sandwich
不该坐在
while you're sitting on the ground where the pigeons shit.
都是鸟屎的地上吃
Whatever.
算了
But they said, you share a...a parking lot with the guys at the dump.
他们说 这停车场和垃圾场共用
So you gotta ask the guys at the dump.
得那帮人同意
No fucking way I'm asking the guys at the dump!
我才不找你们那帮垃圾！
Fuck you.
你才垃圾呢
Fucking assholes.
一帮垃圾
This is good.
真好吃
Yeah, of course it's good.
嗯 当然好
You don't have a sandwich shop, you don't make a good sandwich.
没有金刚钻哪敢开个店
Spicy.
辣辣的
Yeah, calabrian chili, very expensive.
意大利进口辣椒 挺贵的
Agnes.
安尼丝
Huh?
啥？
- Agnes? - Yeah.
- 叫“安你死”？ - 对
Ugh.
难听
Whoa, you sound like the mean guys from the dump.
哎呦 你和那帮人一样坏啊
Hey! I res... I resent that.
喂 我不同意
Those guys are assholes. I'm honest, not an asshole.
那帮人才是垃圾 我说话直 心不坏
You have a son?
你有个儿子？
He's an asshole.
他也是垃圾
Hank.
叫汉克
- Hank is... - Ugh...
- 汉克嘛... - 难听
You don't have to tell me.
不用跟我解释
Sounds too much like the word honk.
听起来像“憨克”
- You have kids? - No.
- 你有孩子吗？ - 绝不
Want some?
不想要吗？
Uh... Well, I can't really imagine myself old.
啊 我想象不到自己老了啥样
You think I imagined myself like this?
你以为我料到变成这样？
No, believe it or not,
不 说实话
I did not think I would end up looking like a yam with a mouth on it.
真没料到自己变成有嘴的山药
But here we are.
现实就这样
It'll happen to you.
该来的总会来
You won't know what hit you.
你根本料不到
Something pretty bad happened to me,
我就碰上一桩噩事
so that's probably why I'm acting weird.
因此才有点不正常呢
How bad?
有多糟？
I guess really bad.
算很糟吧
You don't know it's bad?
你自己不觉得糟吗？
No, I know it's bad.
不 我知道那很糟
But mainly because whenever I tell anyone about it,
只是每次跟人提
they look really scared for me.
他们都大惊小怪
Except for my friend, but she moved away.
除了我那朋友 但她搬走了
And then sometimes I feel bad when I think about it,
我一回想就难受
because...
有时...
I remember moments of it,
会浮现一些瞬间
and I can feel in my body
然后身体会有强烈的
that it was really bad.
排斥反应
But then sometimes I don't think about it, which is weird.
有时我完全不去想 挺怪的
And I feel guilty when I don't think about it.
不想就内疚 像背叛那段痛
Did it just happen?
刚发生的吗？
Is that why you were huffing and puffing?
所以你才喘成那样？
No, it was three...
不 是三年...
a little over three years ago.
是三年多前了
Well, that's not that much time.
好吧 不算太久
I mean, it's a lot of time, but it's not that much time, too.
严格说 也不短了 但也不太长
Yeah.
是啊
Are you...
你...
okay in your house?
家里有人陪你吗？
I have a cat.
我有只猫
Okay.
那好
Olga, what the fuck?
奥宝 别闹
Olga, go to bed.
奥宝 抓紧睡觉
Ugh, Olga, did you shit in my bed?
呃 奥宝 你在我床上便便了？
Ah!
啊！
Oh! Olga, what the fuck?
哦！奥宝 你搞什么啊？
Oh, my God.
天呐
Oh, if you wanted to kill it, you should have just killed it!
想杀就别留它口气啊
Okay. I'm coming back. I'm coming back.
好 我这就来 这就来
It'll be over soon. Okay. Okay.
马上就来 怎么办 怎么办
Okay. What do I need? What am I looking for?
怎么办 需要什么？得找什么来着？
Oh! A bag, a bag! I got a bag!
哦！袋子 袋子 找到个袋子
I'm coming back!
我来了
I'm back, I'm back, I'm so sorry.
回来了 我回来了 真对不起
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
No, no you're not, you're dying.
不 不是说你 你快死了
Get in the bag.
进袋子
Just go in the bag.
快进去
I'm sorry.
对不起了
I'm so sorry.
真对不起了
Oh, God.
哦 天呐
Gavin!
盖文！
Agnes, are you okay?
安尼丝 没事吧？
Agnes? What...
安尼丝？呃...
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Will you come fuck me?
你能来上我吗？
Yes.
好
Wait, wait. I need shoes.
等等 我得穿鞋
I um... I do need shoes.
我呃...真得穿鞋
One second.
等一下
Oh, hey.
哦 嘿
Can I pee?
可以进去小便吗？
Oh, yeah. Definitely.
好 来吧
Can I get in?
我能进去吗？
Oh, in the bath?
哦 进来泡？
Yeah.
嗯
Uh, sure.
嗯 行啊
I'm just gonna turn around here.
我转身换衣
Don't mind me.
你别看
You don't have to hide it.
不用藏着掖着
It's small right now.
现在有点小
Men are so weird.
男人就是怪
Thank you.
谢了
Oh, that's nice.
哦 真好
It's a good temperature.
水温正合适
Thank you.
谢了
I'm embarrassed that I was hiding my dick.
我藏着我的小弟弟 真尴尬
That's okay.
没事
I put my hair over my boobs.
我也用头发遮着胸呢
So true.
的确
I'm sorry the bathtub is so small.
抱歉这浴缸太小
This bathtub?
小吗？
No, it's good.
不 正好
What if I sat behind you?
要不我坐你后面？
- Why? - So, uh...
- 为啥？ - 那就...
it could be like a hug.
就像被抱住
Okay.
好
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-  行吗？ - 行
Oh, wait. Can I look at it?
等下 我能看看吗？
At my dick?
小弟弟？
Yeah.
嗯
Hmm...
嗯...
I've never seen one that soft.
真没见过这么软的
Okay, I think that just gave me nightmares for the next decade.
好啊 十年的噩梦从此开始
No, I mean, you just never get to see them like that.
不是啦 只是 很少有人这样软着给你看
They're better like this.
还是软的好
Okay, I'm done.
好 看完了
Do you think you want the stuff that everyone has?
你想要那种大家都有的事情吗？
What do you mean?
你指什么？
Like, uh, family or whatever. I don't know.
像是家庭之类的 我也不太懂
Do you want that stuff?
你想要吗？
With you?
是和你一起吗？
No.
不
No, I mean, it was your question.
不 你来回答
Yeah. I want that stuff.
嗯 我想要那种事情
Nice.
挺好
Do you?
你呢？
Well...
嗯...
You know, probably just to keep Lydie closer...
只想让利迪住近点
but I don't see it.
但我看不见
See it where?
看什么？
Like, in my head.
看不见那种未来
I don't see myself getting older or having kids.
我看不见自己变老 看不见有孩子
I don't see myself.
也看不见自己
I think you'd be a great mom.
你会是个好妈妈的
Why?
为什么？
You're very nice.
你人很好
I'm not that nice.
没那么好啦
People always say they don't want a kid,
人们开始都说不要孩子
but then things change.
但想法最终会变
What we want and stuff...
我们想要的事情...
I think it changes.
最终会变的
It's too cold.
水凉了
I think it's nice.
我觉得挺好的
“宝贝”相伴的时光
Hi! Yay!
嗨！耶！
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿 嘿 嘿
- I missed you. - I missed you.
- 我想死你了 - 我也想死你了
I missed you so much. Oh, my God.
我太想你了 天呐
Is the baby here?
带宝宝来了吗？
The baby's here. The baby's here.
宝宝来了 宝宝来了
- Hi, Agnes. - Hi, Fran.
- 嗨 安尼丝 - 嗨 弗兰
Fran.
嘿 弗兰
- Yes? - Remember?
- 你说？ - 还记得吗？
Yeah.
嗯
Big day!
大日子！
Definitely.
当然
All right, sweetie...
来吧 宝贝...
So, you're glad you came?
你高兴我们来吗？
I'm so, so, so, so glad.
我超 超 超 超高兴的
And now I know what an exploding vagina looks like.
现在懂了 原来生孩子时阴道会炸裂
Mhmm.
嗯哼
- So be honest. - Mhmm.
- 坦白说吧 - 嗯？
Do you like her?
你喜欢她吗？
- My baby? - Yeah.
- 我的宝宝？ - 对
Yeah. I really like my baby.
喜欢 真太爱我的宝宝了
Well, that's really good.
那真好
And you still like me, right?
你还喜欢我吧？
Yes, Agnes. I love you both.
废话 安尼丝 你俩我都爱
Cool.
好
- Lydie? - Yeah?
- 利迪？ - 在
- Babe, will you grab the baby? - Yeah, of course. One second.
- 宝贝 帮我抱下宝宝吧 - 好 回来聊
- Hey. - Hi.
- 嘿 - 嗨
- You need help with the stuff? - No, no, no.
- 要我帮忙拿吗？ - 没事 不用
- Okay. - Hi.
- 好 - 来
- Hi. - Hi.
- 可好呀 - 好
Look at this.
这儿真不错
Oh, let me grab one.
哦 我来拿一个
No, I love holding them.
不用 我就爱拎包
So, are you... oh, yes.
那么 你...哦 看
Hi. Wow. She has much more of a face.
嗨 哇 小脸长得真漂亮
Mhmm.
嗯嗯
Little freaky baby Janie.
小怪兽简妮
Oh, not Janie. Just doing Jane.
哦 不叫简妮了 叫简就行
【译注 简妮更女性 而简更中性 改名表明偏好中性命名】
Hi, nice to see you again.
嗨 又见到你啦
Oh, oh.
哦 哦
Oh, it's okay.
哦 别怕
Oh, I didn't...
哦 我不是故...
It's okay. It happens all the time.
没关系 这种事常有的
Oh, really, does that happen?
哦 真的吗
Is it my face?
因为我的脸吗？ 呵呵
Hello, is it my face?
因为我的脸吗？
Lighthouse day!
灯塔游！
Lighthouse day.
灯塔游
Fran. Fran. Lighthouse day!
弗兰 弗兰 灯塔游！
Lighthouse day.
灯塔游
Janie, Janie. Lighthouse day!
简妮 简妮 灯塔游！
She actually didn't sleep super well, so.
她昨晚没怎么睡 你懂的
Oh.
哦
Yeah, we're really, really fucking tired.
是啊 我们真的 真的筋疲力尽
Yeah, I don't think she's gonna be in for, like, a big thing today.
她今天不太适合大活动
The baby?
说宝宝吗？
Well, she's just a baby, she could do whatever.
她只是个小宝宝 应该没问题
I mean, not really.
其实不见得
But you two go. I will stay here.
你们俩去吧 我留下来
Oh, really? Okay.
真的？行
I really wanted you to see it.
我真想让你也看看
Babe, I will see it at some point. It's okay.
宝贝 会有机会的 放心
Okay.
好吧
No.
别
No, you two go.
不 你俩都去
No, no, someone has to stay with Jane.
不行 总得有人陪简
I'll do it.
我来
Really?
你确定？
Oh, Jane is actually really particular.
哦 简比较难伺候
I will do it.
交给我吧
Oh, my God. Agnes, thank you so much.
天呐 安尼丝 太谢谢你了
Fran, we're free! We're free.
弗兰 我们自由了！自由了！
The lighthouse is very romantic.
灯塔很浪漫的
You two should be there alone together.
就该你俩去
Make another baby or whatever.
再造个宝宝什么的
Like, twenty minutes, that's it.
就二十分钟 很快的
One question. What if she kills me?
问一下 她会不会把我吃了？
She's not gonna kill you.
她不吃人
Hey...
嘿...
Don't drop her.
别抱掉了
No. I won't drop her.
不会 我抱不掉的
Okay...
好...
Okay.
好了
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Here you go.
给你小兔兔
Thank you.
太谢谢了
- Here you go, babe. - Thank you.
- 给你 宝贝 - 谢谢
Lydie?
利迪？
Yeah?
嗯？
What do I say to her?
我该对她说点啥？
Babe, you don't have to say anything.
宝贝 什么都不用说
Twenty minutes.
就二十分钟
Hi.
嗨
I'm Agnes.
我是安尼丝
Pretty weird you're gonna be a person someday.
真神奇 最终你会长成个独立的人
No offense, but you look insane right now.
别介意 你现在真有点吓人
Skin and just a small amount of hair.
光溜溜 头发很少
Don't worry.
别担心
It won't be like that in a little.
很快会变样的
Is this okay or...
能抱抱你吗？
All right.
行
I'll put you down.
不抱了
Oh. I'll pick you back up.
想要啊 那就再抱起来
Okay, okay, okay.
抱了 抱了 抱了
You're so sweet looking.
你长得真漂亮
When you grow up, you can tell me whatever.
等你长大后 不管什么想法...
Like, if you have a thought and you're like, that's a bad thought,
都可以告诉我 哪怕是个坏念头
I probably had that same thought but, like, ten times worse.
我很可能也有过 而且更坏
So you can just tell me.
所以你尽管说
I'll never be scared by that.
我不会大惊小怪的
If someone does something bad to you...
要是有人对你做了桩噩事...
If someone says something scary...
有人借此闲言碎语 冷嘲热讽...
If you wanna kill yourself with like a pencil or a knife or whatever,
让你想用铅笔 刀之类的东西自尽
you can just tell me.
都可以跟我说
I'll never tell you you're scaring me.
我永远不会评头论足 大惊小怪
I'll just say, yeah. I know.
我只会说 嗯 我知道...
It's just like that sometimes.
事情有时就这样
Yeah.
嗯
I'm sorry
对不起
that bad things are gonna happen to you.
坏事可能会找上你
I hope they don't.
希望不会
If I can ever stop something from being bad, let me know.
要是我能阻止 一定要跟我说
But sometimes bad stuff just happens.
坏事不会给你打招呼
That's why I feel bad for you,
所以我有点心疼你
in a way.
某种程度上
That you're alive and you don't know that yet.
你活着却还体会不到
But I can still listen
但我还是能静心聆听的
and not be scared.
不会大惊小怪
So that's good.
这很好
Or that's something, at least.
至少是点儿安慰
对不起，宝贝
蒙太奇字幕组原创译制 转载须遵循CC BY-NC-SA 4.0协议
翻译：小p 校对：Lei、novaeye、小p 后期：novaeye
Telegram和IRC交流群：MontageSubs
编剧兼导演
伊娃·维克托
制片人
阿黛尔·罗曼斯基
马克·切里亚克 和 巴里·詹金斯
摄影
米娅·乔菲·亨利
剪辑
艾历克斯·奥洛林
兰迪·阿特金斯
配乐
莉亚·欧阳·鲁斯李（李明德）
主演
伊娃·维克托 饰 安尼丝
娜奥米·阿基 饰 闺蜜利迪
主演
路易斯·坎瑟米 饰 教授德克尔
凯莉·麦科马克 饰 校友同事娜塔莎
主演
海蒂安·帕克 饰 法庭律师威尔逊
E. R.·费特迈斯特 饰 利迪配偶弗兰
主演
卢卡斯·赫奇斯 饰 邻居盖文
约翰·卡洛·林奇 饰 三明治店老板皮特
对不起，宝贝
（A24影业）